But as you start talking about these
things, I just sit here and I start
churning, you know, and and my brain's
like, "This is what you're going to do
right after you get off this podcast in
LA."
>> Best part of Viking when you can just,
you know, critical think, right?
>> Yeah, dude.
Some of the most fun I've had this year
hacking already was with you guys in the
CTVB Adobe hackalong that we did a
couple weeks ago. And the results were
great. We found four figures worth of
bugs in just 2 hours. And I just want to
shout out Adobe for being such an
amazing program, for sponsoring the
podcast, for staying involved in the bug
bounty community. Um, and I just wanted
to say if you guys want to check out a
new program, the Adobe program is
awesome. They've got scope for days,
guys. They've got binaries, they've got
open source projects, they've got
enterprise products, they've got web
apps, they got wild cards, they got
mobile apps. Anything you would want to
hack on, the freaking Adobe program has
it. The bounties are competitive. And I
mean, just look at the um look at the
thanks tab on hacker 1, right? and
filter for this year. There's already uh
somebody with 620 reputation uh from
Adobe, right? So, this guy's out here
like don't tell them about Adobe. I'm
killing it. I don't don't want anybody
to know about it. Um so, yeah, it's a
program right for opportunity,
especially in the area of AI hacking
because they're shipping a lot of AI
related code right now and they really
value AI submissions coming through the
Bug Bunny program. So, if you want a a
new program to hack on, I recommend
Adobe. They're great.
Sup hackers. We got the this week in bug
bounty segment real quick. First item on
the docket is integrity has launched
their ambassador program. So if you're
deep in the uh integrity ecosystem and
you want to take that a step further, I
have it um you know firsthand talking to
the head of uh community over at
Integrity that they're really trying to
bump up uh the amount of community
engagement and involvement that they
have this upcoming year. So they're
really going to be supporting the
Integrity ambassadors a lot. Um, so you
can find out how to apply for that at
integrity.com/amassadors.
Um, you know, it's a annual thing.
They'll give you support on, you know,
engaging with the integrity community
wherever you're at in various spots
around the world. Um, and give you
access to resources that you'll need to
drive that community. So, um, really
good opportunity. Uh, I definitely think
you guys should take advantage of it if
you're in the integrity ecosystem. All
right. Next up is Adobe and Hack the
Bay. Um, the Adobe team wanted us to let
you know that they're going to be at
Hack the Bay this year. That is March uh
23rd, I want to say. Yep. Uh, 11:00 to
5:00 p.m. in San Francisco. So, if
you're around and you're in the Bug
Bounty world and you're going to Hack
the Bay, your new mission is to go find
the Adobe team and say hi. Tell them you
heard on the CTBB podcast to come and
say hi. That's a great way to support us
and a great way to engage with a a
staple program in the community, uh,
Adobe. So, if you're going to be at Hack
the Bay, definitely go by and say hi to
them. They'd love to meet you, and
that's a great way to support the pod.
Um, last but not least, we have another
shout out for the Bug Bounty maturity
framework. Um, for any of you program
managers that are listening, if you're
looking to um, understand how your
booking program is on a maturity scale
from emerging to leading and what you
need to do to take it to the next level
with your program from a hacker's
perspective, but also just from a
well-run program perspective, then bug
bounty maturity framework is an awesome
tool that you guys can use um, to make
sure your hackers are getting the best
experience and you're getting the most
value out of your bug bounty program. I
know the guy running it, Steve, he used
to work with us at the pod. He's amazing
and knows exactly what he's doing. He's
like one of the best people to run this
in the community that I can even
possibly think of. So, shout out to
Steve. All right, that's it for the
Twib. Let's hit the show.
All right, look, dude. Here's the deal.
Last week on the pod, you told me that I
need to be like actively training Claude
and getting it to
>> No, no, you're triggering me. No, stop
now already. I hate it when people use
the word training wrong.
>> No, I know. And I and I know you know,
but listen, every normie out there and
you I'm not trying to be offensive or
anything, but people who are just not
>> fine tuning the model. I know.
>> Yeah. People say training and I'm like
like you know they're like oh I trained
my chat GPT to do this like you did no
training. You gave it some context. You
gave it a prompt. You didn't train.
>> Fair. Let me rephrase. You guide my
claude.
>> Yes.
>> Inform my claude. Equip my claude with
what I wanted to do. Um,
>> and I played around with it a little bit
more and you know, you've been tweeting
up a storm about claude finding stuff
and I have seen these findings firsthand
and they're legit. Um, and yeah, we're
just kind of at a point where you need
to be using Claude to hack. And that's
why we, you know, we push Kaido and you
helped them build the Claude skill for
for um for Kaido. Um, so what I want to
do today is I want to talk a little bit
more about skills, how to understand
skills. And I know I I know I could see
your face right now. I know that you are
a little uncomfortable talking about
this because this is kind of the secret
sauce, the last secret sauce that there
is.
>> Yeah. Well, I think I've I'm multiple
fronts. One is I already know there is
some hesitancy around talking about AI
on the pod too much. And Bus Factor
himself has already been like, "I'm so
tired." Not not about the pod, but just
about like the community and and X and
everything. And I know that tons of tons
of people we know are like muting lots
of words about Cloud Code and agents and
everything else on on X. And you know,
again, I'll say we've said hundred
times. It's like this just is important
enough for us to tell you. You know,
it's kind of like when your parents keep
telling you to pick up your room. It's
like, well, you're going to have to do
it when you get older. Right. It's like
>> Exactly.
>> You're going to have to give the people
what they want. We're here to give the
people what they need, you know? And
that is that is one of the truest
statements Justin has ever said about
this podcast. He lives and dies by that
mantra. So,
>> um, so yeah,
>> it's hard too, man. I mean, we we we we
try all the time there is the pull of
like, oh wow, we'd get so many more
views, so much more distribution if we
would just talk about XYZ.
>> Yeah,
>> we we don't do it, guys. We don't
freaking do it. And
>> how many people have told you to do more
beginner content?
>> Yeah. Yeah. many many many times, you
know, and and uh you know, I I won't do
it. So, anyway, this is what you guys
need even if it's not what you want.
>> Oh, I didn't answer your question. Sorry
to cut you off, but you said I'm
hesitant to talk about it. And yes, I
am. Honestly, Justin, I would not have
talked about this or another future
episode we have coming up in in a in a
few weeks or maybe maybe it's more than
a month away, but about this sauce, like
giving away the secret sauce for so much
of this because I do think it's like
it's it's an edge. It's leverage.
because I'm willing to scale to more
CloudMax subscriptions to find more bugs
across all bug bounty programs. When we
talk about this, it is giving stuff
away. But, you know, we've we've we've
wrestled with this with the podcast for
the last, you know, two or three years
with the same stuff, right? You're often
giving away techniques on here and so do
our guests. And so, I think it's like
just a part of what we do. And so, yeah,
we'll talk about
>> it. It is. So, we'll see what we can do.
And and we'll see how far we can get
today. Uh, and I I just I do want to
like give you a little bit of an out
here though. Like
>> yeah,
>> if I am asking things that you really
think are going to hack up the secret
sauce for you, you know, like
AI is a little bit different than
talking about techniques. Cuz one of the
things we've built this pod about on is
like coming on here and talking about
stuff pretty liberally
>> and then just betting that, you know,
the community doesn't have the either
the grit or the the patience or, you
know, whatever to actually implement it,
right? Uh and that's why we don't lose
out on our bounties as much. We've been
burned by that many times. Uh and they
it turns out, you know, a lot of you
guys, the people that are the highle
hackers that are listening, we'll take
the techniques and go do it, right? And
that's exactly, you know, what we're
doing. We're exchanging the these
concepts for your trust in your ears,
right? Um, that being said, AI is a
little bit different because if you just
do the thing, AI, you know, and tell it
to do the thing, then AI will just do
it, right? You don't have need any like
grit or endurance, right? So,
>> I don't know, man. It's I will give you
an out if you if you want to not say
some of the stuff. You feel free to like
just shush me along a little bit. Okay.
>> Sure. Yep. Sounds good.
>> All right. So, first up, man, let's
let's let's get into this. This is going
to be a nuts and bolts episode. Um, I've
got a, you know, rubber meets the road
question for you a little bit here. So,
I don't use a ton of cloud skills. The
only cloud skill I really use right now
is the Kaido mode cloud skill. Um,
I kind of feel like cloud skills are
limiting Claude a little bit. Like, if I
tell it, hey, here's my super cool thing
to like, uh, you know, uh, grab all the
lazy loaded JS files or whatever, right,
from from the the JS that I gave you. um
and then it's like a little off
>> then Claude's you know Claude's gonna
try to use the skill and like oh it
doesn't work you know or whatever and
then it's gonna go and get distracted or
whatever whereas I feel like Claude is
smart enough where it's like I tell it
to go download all the lazy loaded files
it'll write up a little script in like
30 seconds to pull it down and it's
perfectly tailored to the situation.
>> Yeah.
>> So are we sort of hampering our cloud
skills or our cloud when we are giving
it cloud skills versus just telling it
to do the thing or are we actually
enabling them? Yeah, I think that it's
just it really depends on what you're
asking it to do, right? Like maybe lazy
or like loading lazy loaded JavaScript
files is something that it's like really
good at, right? But you do need skills
for things it's not good at like Kaido.
Like like you why why didn't you just
get rid of your Kaido skill? It's like
if you ask it to start with Kaido, it's
going to have to go into some deep
research. If it can't find the docs
online, it might legitimately not be
able to figure it out. But if there's
really good docs online, it would go
find the docs. it would download, you
know, it would figure out what the SDK
is. It would go look at the GitHub open
source code and it would be able to
figure it out. But now you've wasted
like, you know, half of your 5 hour
limit for it figuring out how to use
Kaido. And so I so I think that um you
know, I've kind of categorized when it's
useful to have skills into a couple
buckets. The one that we're talking
about right now is basically things it
doesn't know. And that could be because
you have a custom setup. Like let's say
you have a server and it runs at a
certain IP address and you have a
certain user on there and you want
things to be done a certain way. That's
in your head. There's no way for cloud
to figure it out. And so you probably
need a skill or to update your cloud MD
to say like hey when you're using my VPS
here's the password or here's how you
connect to it or here's where I save
things. Like you know you basically need
to give cloud code information it
doesn't have. And I think that also
applies to any kind of like
groundbreaking techniques. you know,
these models are trained on trillions of
tokens and your uh specific technique,
especially if you got it from like last
year's DevCon talk or something that
you're using to exploit some sort of
like, you know, nested GraphQL mutation.
GraphQL is maybe a good a bad example
because clock's so good at GraphQL, but
you know, there are definitely things
that it's not as good at or that it just
doesn't know because it's not been in
the training data. It may very well be
able to figure it out given enough time
and effort, but why not just give it
like a head start,
>> okay? you know,
>> so custom.
>> But see, but then there's also the
inverse of that, man. I feel like like
just to challenge you there a little
bit. I mean, that's that pretty much the
exact opposite of what I just said,
which is,
>> you know, if we give it skills
>> Mhm.
>> that that
>> that are not applicable to all of the
situations.
>> Yeah.
>> Then, you know, we're the the whole
technological advance that we have here
is that it's smart.
>> Yeah. You know, like I feel like giving
it skills is like just why didn't we
just code it, you know, right? Am I
wrong there? Or is it like is the beauty
of AI that it can actually go figure out
the more nuanced situation without us
having to give it instructions on how to
deal with that?
>> I mean, I think it it's definitely both.
Like it has a lot of information baked
in. You're not you're not wrong about
that. But then it clearly has
limitations, right? Like using Kaido
mode and then it's smart enough to
figure out some stuff, but it's not
smart enough to figure out everything. I
think that uh your concern can mostly be
mitigated with like just a cla MD line
like one line that says like hey when I
ask you to do something like invoke the
skill to do it because sometimes I have
certain ways I want things to be done
but if the skill isn't comprehensive
enough or if it fails or if you try with
it and it doesn't work don't stop there
use your own exploration your own
creativity to keep going you know try
harder put the OCP motto straight
straight in your thing you know I have
PC or GTFO and try harder both in my
cloud MD because it's like I'm not like
you can't just say oh this looks like it
might be vulnerable that's that's not
valuable to me I want you to actually
have a full PC that I can you know uh
completely validate end to end to make
sure this is an actual bug and so I
think that
>> um you know the limitation is mostly
mitigated by what you're talking about
but there have been a lot of studies
that have shown that like poorly written
agent MD or claude MD files or poorly
written skills actually reduce the
quality and so I I do think people
should be really um careful in
particular about how like what they're
adding and how they're adding it.
>> Yeah. Yeah, I agree. It it is a little
tricky though, man, because I do find
myself like I definitely just gave
Claude a list of like things I wanted to
brute force the other day and said like,
"Hey, you know, brute force these in in
Kaido, you know, and it like made a
bunch of replay sessions or whatever. It
didn't actually use automate. I don't
know, maybe I told it to use replay
sessions or whatever." And I was like,
"Dang, I could have just like put this
straight into automate myself." Like,
what am I doing? I'm getting lazy as
heck. Um, so it is a little tricky. Um,
>> so building off of what you just said
though, I wanted to like describe
something that I uh saw in the Kaido
mode skill that that you and Kaido built
and ask your opinion on this as a
framework for Kaido skills. So
>> what will happen in the Kaido skill Kaid
mode skill is if it can do something
>> with the Kaido skill you know
documentation that you guys have built
and stuff like that it will invoke your
B your binaries or your your scripts or
whatever that you have in place and it
will do it with that right if it cannot
do that it will um use the actual
clientJS
library that thets files that run kind
of the Kaido skill um is built off of
and it will invoke those directly to
accomplish its goal, right? And it will
sometimes even do that if it if it's a
more complicated action because it'll be
like I'll just write out the script and
chain multiple actions together, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Um and then if it cannot get it with
that, it will then try to use GraphQL to
control Kaido directly.
>> Yeah. And I think that sort of fall back
nature, I don't know if you guys you
coded this directly into the Kaido skill
itself, but I think that sort of fall
back iteration nature
>> of building a skill, it works really
well because you give it multiple tiers
of flexibility and control
>> while also abstracting away the tasks
that you know are going to be the same
every single time. Does that make sense?
>> Yeah. I didn't think there was going to
be anything I didn't want to mention,
but there is something that I'm not
willing to mention, but I have
implemented something very similar for
tough problems in Bug Bounty. um where
basically it's exactly that like I want
you to try to solve the problem with
this method but if it doesn't work for
some reason then try this method and if
that doesn't work then try this one. Um
and I think you're right that gives it a
lot of of flexibility and a lot of um
like a much higher odds of success. And
no I I didn't build that into the skill.
It's really funny that your cloud code
did that. Um,
>> I wonder if that's a claude I wonder if
that's a claude code like concept that
that Anthropic built into Claude Code.
Like, hey, you know, if if the skill
doesn't work, look at the primitives
that built the skill.
>> Yeah.
>> And then try to use those primitives to
accomplish the same goal
>> or not. I don't know.
>> I think it's probably just the
fine-tuning on lots of data, especially
lots of coding things where it tried to
run something on the command line and it
failed. And normally, you know, a year
ago or whatever, the models were like
fine-tuned to basically just like stop
at that point because like
>> all the examples were like one-offs. But
where people have been using cloud code
over the course of the last year, they
probably have lots of training data for
examples of it like failing, trying
again, failing, trying again. That being
like the ideal training set because
that's what we want as users. We just
want it to work. Like stop getting the
error and make it work.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Just force it. All right. So
given that I I understand that that
makes sense.
We're going to create skills and we are
going to you know give it sort of this
fallback architecture which is good.
What things do I create skills for is is
kind of like my next question where
where I go because
>> a lot of this is just like looking at at
the JS files, looking at the HTTP
request and like
>> trying things which is great you know
and the Kaido modal is phenomenal by the
way. It really is super helpful for to
have it like you know sending stuff uh
through replay and being able to have
introspection to it. But you know what
what areas should we be building skills
in? Do you do you have any
>> I I think I think when there's something
very flexible like making requests
>> and you have a way you want it to make
requests that's a great place for a
scale right like it can use curl it can
use javascript it can use python it can
use kaido it can use wget like it can
use chrome dev tools it can use
playright I think um in general anytime
there is a way to do like there's many
many ways to do something and you want
it to do a specific way it's a great
time to use a skill right like you want
it to use kaido so you can co-hack with
it so you can see the request so that
you have history for screenshots for
PC's. I want to do that for the same
reason, right? There are probably lots
of things like that. Like if it's going
to SSH or SCP things to a certain place,
it's like, oh, it needs to know what
server to do that to. It needs to know
where to save that thing. Another great
example would be like where do you want
it to take notes? Do you want it to save
at the target level or at the subdomain
level? Do you want it to save off leads
and findings or or just um gadgets? you
know like I think these sort of things
where the the um the total output space
especially across multiple sessions so
actually that's that's another great
example let's say Justin that you are
going to be hacking with cloud code a
lot over the next week do you want each
cloud code instance to save files in
different folder structures it doesn't
make any sense right it's going to
confuse you and your desk is going to or
your um desktop or like you know your
file system is going to be a total messy
man
>> well yeah but it doesn't have to be
messy you actually can just use a scale
or cloud MD like to actually you know a
line in your cloud MD or a paragraph in
there or whatever to steer it to behave
in the way you want it to that's not
restricting it like telling it where to
save it isn't going to degrade the
quality right telling it how to make
those requests will hopefully not
degrade the quality though I do think
it's like much better at like bun ts
stuff or like you know
>> Oh yeah I think so yeah
>> yeah it's like really really good
>> because they bought bun right you know
it's like
>> yeah clearly like they're they're you
know smoking their own supply over there
with that I think
>> well what's kind of crazy is that
whatever they have cloud code do is
probably going to be by default like if
you don't steer it is probably what's
going to dominate the market because
everyone's using it and everyone's going
to continue to use it and so they kind
of have like really large influence over
that but
>> um
>> but anyways back to your question so I
think that that's one way right it's
like when the total problem space is
large or the total solution space is
large and you want it to find a solution
in a certain way it's a good time to
implement a skill or to update your
you're cloud MD. The other time is when
it's knowledge that like secret
knowledge um you know like I don't know
>> hidden techniques that you that you have
that I don't right or I or you know
there are probably Google gadgets that
are in my files that are not in your
files. And so like bundling those into a
skill makes sense. It's not on the
internet. It's not in it's not in you
know the public domain where it can go
find it. So if it needs this this
gadget, this oracle for ID to username
or something for some random bug bounty
program, it needs to either be in the
note so it gets out of the context
whenever it's hacking that program or it
needs to be in a skill, right? And and
you know that's not going to limit it.
That's going to make it way better
because it has access to more tools,
right? Um I guess that's another good
example. Skills are a great like there
are things that AI could sign up for but
is really going to struggle to sign up
for. So another place for anam another
place for a skill to be implemented
would would be like
>> let's say you wanted it to use a
specific piece of software that requires
you going through enterprise sales to
buy like
by by not having a skill there. It just
literally can't use that product. But if
you've signed up you've got cred you've
got API token and you make a skill and
you put the token and how to call it the
skill now it can use that. So like it's
literally like a skill you're giving it
that it could not have had otherwise.
>> Yeah, that that makes sense. that that I
don't struggle with at all. Like if I
need to give it access to, you know,
>> Kaido or, you know, whatever enterprise
thing that I needed to have access to,
>> then that makes total sense for a skill.
What I'm kind of struggling with from
like conceptual perspective from as an
offensive security researcher is stuff
like
>> for example I thought about well totally
you could do that for sure but but I'm
thinking like do I create something like
a front-end analysis skill where where I
like outline my methodology for doing
front-end analysis you know and and
doing client side hacking essentially
right mapping out the attack surface
understanding you know everything about
it or do I and and do I give it tools to
do that, right? Like, hey, here's, you
know, use Prettyier for
beautifification, use this for source
map enumeration, you know, that sort of
thing. uh and and will giving it that be
helpful and is or am I just turning it
into me and I'm losing the the magic of
like wow it found something that you
know like for example when I talked
about the the shift um you know the
shift vulnerability that it found I I
told it hey try some JWT attacks is what
I told it on this target right and then
it just went through and did all the JWT
attacks right you know that it knew and
it found a bug and it was like a 15k
crit you know
>> so I I think there are two things here.
The the first thing is
>> you already answered this question, but
yeah.
>> No, no, no, no, no. Actually, no. All
the stuff you said triggered completely
new thoughts to me. The the first one is
that tokens are cheap for right now,
right? They're subsidized. So, you
always should just do both if you have
the opportunity. I think it's amazing.
And I think that if you really wanted to
know, you should compare it and improve
your workflow. So, I think personally,
you should actually hardcode your front
end analysis because it gives you more
determinism. So, you know that it's not
going to miss things that you wouldn't
have missed, right? like like because
when you just let it explore by itself,
it might not have actually loaded source
maps. It might not have been able to
find them. And unless you're literally
watching it the whole time, which you're
clearly not, you're doing other things,
you're hacking other stuff. When it says
it's done, you're just going to be like,
"Oh, okay. I guess it didn't find that
anything." It's like, "No, no, no.
Actually, it missed this entire workflow
that I normally do." And so, I think
especially, you know, if you want to be
thorough, you should outline your
methodology and make it follow that. But
then, I think you should do a completely
separate run that's like that has none
of that that does its own thing. And
then if you have the opportunity,
compare them and be like, "Hey, was
there anything that this like free
roaming agent found that our hard-coded
workflow didn't find? If so, how did it
do that?" And add that to the workflow.
Like what techniques did it use that we
don't that we didn't like previously
hardcode into the workflow?
>> That's a great point. I think I think
that's some very helpful feedback to
give. And so let's get into the nuts and
bolts of that because I think what's
overwhelming for everybody right now is
this is like, you know, such a new
world, you know, and and getting defined
pathways for like improvement and
implementation of AI is really helpful.
So let's say let's give an example. Um
I've got this website site.com that I I
want to hack on.
>> So I spit up, you know, maybe I've got
my T-Mox pane. I've got two windows side
by side. one, I like clone down all of
my own, you know, skills and and agent
definitions and stuff like that into
that that cloud code instance and I say
boom, hacksite.com, here's the cookies,
here's whatever you need. Here's like my
my, you know, starter pack or whatever.
Uh, and then the other in the other
window I have it I say just hey
hacksite.com you know very few skills
very few resources
>> and then
>> do I I mean do you think I should ask it
for like a definitive output? Should I
say like okay both of you guys output a
report that contains everything that you
found that you think might be of
interest and then compare the two and
crosscorrelate or
>> for me here. Personally, if I was going
to do it, I would say, you know, once I
feel like both are kind of done, I would
just say or or actually maybe while
they're running because it might have to
compact most multiple times. So, I would
I would tell both when when starting
them. And mine kind of do this naturally
because of my cloud MD, but keep notes
on what you're doing and what you tried
and what was successful and what wasn't.
And then and then at the end, I would
say like, "Hey, give me a list of all
the things you tried and you know, the
workflow you went through and all your
findings um to to just one of them. It
doesn't matter which one. and then just
paste that into the other and be like,
"Hey, I had another agent work. This is
what it did. Compare it to what you did
and tell me about any gaps like what did
it find you didn't? What did you find it
didn't? And what did you try that it
didn't?" Vice versa. And then when you
know that after after it responds, it
might be insightful, it might not. If
it's insightful, say like, "Oh, okay,
perfect. Now add that to our workflow so
you don't miss that next time."
>> That's really nice because especially
with the agent you're asking it of, it's
got its context already. So it's like oh
I did try that but then I like cut it
last minute and but if you added asked
third agent
>> to like you know
>> from both of them
>> I almost said take read the output of
both but no it's lossy like you
definitely want to do it with the
context.
>> That's interesting. I bet you could also
improve it even further though by saying
third agent look at the context files
for both of the other agents. Yeah.
>> And see what it tried
>> uh and compare that to the outputs of
each.
>> Yep. uh and you know compare and
contrast.
>> I I'm I'm very often using this skill
that I made called session search. It's
not a big deal, but it's just like a
small little CLI wrapper around like a
fast, you know, rip grab across all of
my session logs. So I think I'm up to
like 4 gigabytes worth of session logs
in cloud code just on my local laptop,
not including the stuff that runs in the
cloud.
>> And um I'll often say like, "Hey, I was
chatting with you about YAML parsers
yesterday or like a few a few days ago
and I don't know where the session is.
Can you go find that? Or another thing
I've used it for, hacker 1's API token.
It only lets you have one at a time. And
a lot of times I'll like lose my token
or don't know where it's at. I should
just put in one password. But I but I'll
be like, "Hey, go grab for BB scope and
grab the token that we used in that
command. I need to use it for something
else, you know, or what have you."
>> Do you give it access to one password?
>> No.
>> Yeah. Okay. because I know some people
that do that for like uh you know open
claw or whatever and I'm like
>> oh my gosh like don't do that.
>> I mean
>> well I mean I do think I'm still running
pretty risky like I use dangerous to
skip permissions on everything and and I
have it running on my local laptop with
access to everything
>> but I don't give it access to my email
or to one password so I'm I'm at least a
little protected.
>> That's good. That's good. Um, okay. So,
yes to my methodology for the purpose of
determinism to
>> deter Yeah. Determinism and confidence
that it's doing what I want it to do.
>> Yes.
>> But also,
>> but tell it not to limit itself. Yeah. I
would say just even put it in your
skill. Like don't limit yourself to this
workflow. If you find something
interesting, go down that rabbit hole
and then just come back to the workflow.
or after we're done, if you run through
my whole workflow and there's stuff that
you thought was cool or like that we
should have checked that we didn't add
it back to this skill and keep going.
>> Freaking crazy that we're saying that
you thought was cool to a computer. Like
that's insane, bro.
>> Yeah, it is.
>> Wow. You just like authentically
recommended that you ask a computer to
go look into what it thought was cool.
Like that's nuts, dude. And it's like,
you know, I'm obviously conflicted
because I don't think I I don't think
that these models are in any way
conscious, but they definitely emulate
humans and like all of their thought
patterns and all of their token output.
So stuff like that just works.
>> It is crazy, dude. It really is. Um,
okay. So, can you give us a couple? So,
I really liked the session session
search
uh skill that you mentioned. Um, do you
have any other skills that you want to
just lob up there? You don't you don't
need to release them. just talk.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, uh, one skill that is,
uh, really good and, uh, you should not
let it take away from buying his book.
So, go buy Eugene's book. But JD XSS
doctor created a skill that he and I
both use called zero day research that
basically told it to go look at Eugene's
book slash all of his content that he's
put out online and create and create
like a zero day finder. And it's really
good at looking at uh source code and
it's really good at looking at binaries.
So like executables and like Mac OS DMGs
and stuff. It's re like I don't know why
but like I think that it's because you
know there's not a lot of uh the
internal monologue of experts like like
Eugene's brain for this sort of thing in
the training set. So this is like
another example where it's like a kind
of like secret knowledge that you know
eventually will be baked into the model
but right now it's not. And so you can
um you know you can have it like search
for zero days. That's a good one. Um
content creator/report writer. I think
everyone should have their own. And
personally I think that I'll just give
you some prompting tips right now. Give
it an example of like some of your best
written reports and tell it to keep
everything super concise and super
technical and just straightforward. Like
don't put any flavor in it. And then
give it exact fields that you want it to
fill out every single time. And this
saves me so much time. And like you know
my agents at the once they find a
finding like I tell them to go ahead and
write the report and then give me a link
to it locally and they're just they're
so good like I very seldom have to edit
them very much at all. Um I'm usually
reading them for accuracy not for any
kind of tone. The tone is just like and
then I did this and then I did this and
then this happened. It doesn't inject
any flavor or overhypeness. It's just
like you know I mean it's very
straightforward and so that can be
really useful.
>> Yeah dude. I don't know man. it like
Richard, you can bleep bleep the name
out here, but like I've I've looked at
reports recently and uh like that are AI
generated and I I had to give them a
talking to about it to be honest. I'm
like this is not good and this is why
you know people are are uh you know
having issues with AI generated reports.
So I think you really have to you know I
think giving that recommendation
>> to anybody who is uh you know not at a
at a higher level of hacking proficiency
and hasn't written a thousand plus
reports by hand. Yeah.
>> You know
>> it's a little dangerous.
>> Let me talk about the ways that it falls
apart so people are aware.
>> It falls apart in the fact that it will
often blend bugs. Like very frequently
it tries to blend two or three bugs into
a single report which just doesn't make
sense. and and I'm often having to clear
that up. The other thing is it's like
it's understanding of threat modeling is
still kind of bad. Um there was a report
that um I put in yesterday or the day
before um and what happened was it was
access to a bunch of pay like um free
features or a bunch of paid features. So
it was a bunch of payw wall bypasses,
right? And those normally aren't great
reports, but I mean it was like 30 plus
features like you could get access to
basically any pro pro or enterprise
feature. But the the agent was like in
the report like saying like complete
degradation of security. Like basically
a lot of the payw wall things allowed
you to like change things about your
object in this in this app that made it
less secure. And so it was convinced
that it was like bad because you could
like payw wall bypass to get like
enterprise features to then make the
product less secure.
>> Less secure.
>> Yeah. It's like it just doesn't make any
sense. So I mean just be really careful
and read it. But I will say I I don't
have to edit mine very often. Um,
>> yeah, you probably have good good now
and I was about to say training. Holy
crap. No, you have good guidance in
>> good intuition there. Yeah. Um, some
other good skills I think like um BB
scope and um like H1 scope or hacker
scope or whatever that Patrick just came
out with can be really useful because
this is data that the model can't get on
its own. And um basically what his I
think Patrick's is actually an MCP but
>> uh but what it does is it pulls like the
policy page which is really useful
because I previously wasn't giving that
to my agent. So sometimes going out of
scope and having issues and so it it
pulls the policy, it pull it pulls the
scope and then it pulls like um what are
they called? Um disclosed public bug
reports. So it kind of like can get a
heristic for like what might be
vulnerable like
>> what is that called?
>> Uh I think it's called H1 scope. Um
we'll link it in the show notes, but
it's by Patrick.
>> It's a really nice skill and he's and
he's and he's updating like he's even
doing like a blog series right now where
he's already posted two blogs in the
blog series. Um, so that is a nice one.
>> H1 Brain maybe. Is that Is that the MCP
server?
>> Yeah, it is. Yeah, H1 Brain. Um, I spoke
over you, but yeah, that's what Justin
was saying. It's called H1 Brain. Um,
>> okay.
>> Yeah, I think that's mostly, you know,
the types of things if you have any
workflows like I do think skills are
really nice for Justin, you probably
have actually a couple of these in your
hacking workflow where like you very
frequently want to like this. I don't
love this example, but basically get
subdomains, pipe through HTTPX, then
automatically fuzz, and then get all of
those results. Anytime you have like a
full pipeline, it's great to bake it
into a skill so that you're not always
having to like kick it off, especially
if there's like contextual flags or
contextual input where the AI can
basically get that input for you, run
the pipeline for you, and then tell you
where the output is. It's just really
nice to kind of like have like a faster
automation or like a contextual wrapper
for your automation.
>> Yeah. And you're you're using I mean
skill just I just want to like clarify
this here. Skill is being used kind of
loosely here, right? Like it can just be
an MD file with information.
>> It almost always is, but yeah, sometimes
it includes
>> command line tools
>> like
>> Okay. Like a command line tool bundled
with it and and
>> in your experience, it's best to have
Claude write that, you know, using uh
like TypeScript files or something like
that, right?
>> Almost almost always that's what mine
are these days. Yeah. And I think it's
just and that's just because that's what
Claude prefers. And so my intuition says
that it's going to be better at writing
those and make less mistakes when it
writes them. So that's what I've been
letting it do even though I'm not a huge
TypeScript guy.
>> So okay, let's let's just think about
this for a second. Like I think the
highest value thing that somebody can do
right now is who's actively hacking and
using Claude
>> uh and wants to use Claude to integrate
you know into their workflow is just
download the the Kaido mode skill and
just let it like you can just tell it
hey make all these replay tabs like look
at all the stuff that I've got in there
right
>> let me let me give a pro tip for that um
>> I don't know how you do it but like
let's say
>> you're looking at your HTTP history and
you're like oh I want cloud code to hack
on this request what I what I usually do
is I'll copy and paste the top two lines
because it has the host and the path and
then I give that to Claude and say,
"Hey, look at you know this request and
it then it will go find it based on
that." Uh I don't know if the ID on the
left is like matches the ID in the
database and all that. So, that's like
kind of like a really um like a pro tip
that people probably need for like
helping.
>> I tell I tell it the session name in
Kaido is what I typically do.
>> What do you mean?
>> In replay like
>> Oh, in replay. Gotcha. Yeah. No,
>> I'm just doing it straight from my
YouTube history a lot of times.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, that makes sense. That's good.
Yeah. So, but like what is what are the
other I guess like 8020 pieces of like
uh you know you're going to get very
outsized returns. I I've gotten very
outsized returns by hooking it into
Kaido. I think that's you know amazing.
>> Yeah. So I think I think the biggest
second thing that everyone has to do I
guess it's two things. One is update
your cloud MD for just like contextual
information about you because it's going
to make it not reject you as much. Like
you just need to say in your cloud MD,
you don't have to tell it its name, but
you can just say like, "Hey, I'm a bug
bounty hunter. I do ethical testing.
Anything I ask you to look at will be in
scope, but make sure you like attempt to
stay in scope because it's been going
out of scope sometimes lately." Um,
>> no destructive actions.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Don't do destructive actions
unless it's accounts that you know we
own because it's like, you know, I told
you that it's two accounts that we own
that are in Kaido or whatever.
>> And and then the second big thing is
just the note structure. And um I was
going to do an episode where I talk
maybe more deeply about it, but just
right now my intuition says that the
best way to categorize things is like
notes, leads, and leads can be
slashinteresting finding SL whatever.
And then gadgets or primitives. I think
the word primitive might be more
specific for what's in the training set.
So maybe call it primitives then than
findings. And then I have a validator. I
think you should probably write a
validator. Basically, the information
you want to give the validator is things
like, hey, corores issues are often
false positives. BXS, unless you
actually get a trigger to our actual
like trigger output, isn't a valid
finding just because it bypasses the W.
Um, when you go to validate this bug, be
skeptical. Don't mark everything as a
critical or a high. In general, I think
these are lows, these are mediums, these
are highs. like give it really give it
real examples of these bugs and then and
then you have the validator there maybe
as a skill or maybe as a as a sub agent
or just
>> I was going to say that's probably a
good you know we we were talking about
before we got on air like the difference
between skills and agents and you were
saying you don't use agents actually
very much at all that might be a good
>> use case for an agent because you want
it to be unbiased by the other
information you know I like that yeah
>> yeah and so and then so I have a
validator and then I have what's called
reports so my hierarchy is basically
notes, leads, gadgets, findings,
reports, and it kind of flows in like a
really nice way where there's more at
the bottom. It should take notes on all
kinds of stuff and then it should, you
know, some of those will be gadgets,
some of those or sorry, some of those
will be leads or gadgets and then some
of those will become findings and then
some of those will become reports and so
it's like a funnel.
>> Nice. I like that, dude. That's a good
that's a good structure.
>> Yeah. So, so our so so our
three-prongong attack based on your your
question, just to re reframe it for
everybody, is basically you you you need
a Kaido skill. You need you need a cloud
MD that talks about, hey, you're doing
bug bounty hunting. Stay in scope. Don't
do directive actions. Always take notes.
And then you need to tell it where to
take notes, right? Write in this
database or write in this notion. I know
Gret loves notion, so he has it right to
notion. Some people love Obsidian, so
put it in these Obsidian notes so you
can go back and reference them. Um or or
or actually push it to an API, right?
Like so one thing I've been thinking
about doing is just creating like a API.
and having it right there so that
whether it's on my VPS or my personal
machine, all leads and gadgets go there.
And so now no matter where I'm hacking
from, I I have access to those gadgets
and Claude has access to those gadgets.
>> That's pretty freaking good, dude.
>> That's pretty freaking good.
>> Damn. Okay. All right. So, let's let's
talk about orchestration a little bit.
Um so we another component of this is
like okay obviously
seriously listeners you must be using
cloud code to pair hack with you like
that is not really something that you
can avoid doing at this point.
>> Yeah I I I've I've also not posted about
many other people who message me and say
thank you so much just found my first
bug. Thank you so much I just escalated
my you know blind surf into a full read.
Thank you so much. Like I found 10 bugs
in the last week. I'm not joking. Um,
actually, yeah. Well, actually, I won't
make him bleep it. Basically, somebody
you know really well messaged me and was
like, "I found 10 Heisen crits in the
last week by using Glock."
>> That's crazy, man. That's crazy. Yeah, I
think I knew who you're talking about.
We'll compare afterwards. Um, but yeah,
that's I think something everybody must
be doing. Um,
one of the problems that you run into is
how do you make it be persistent? Like,
how do you force it? I know that you
you've mentioned some Ralph loop or
something like that. Um, and I've seen
another I think solution by Kaparthi at
one point. Uh, do you have any best
practices you want to shout out there on
that?
>> Sure. This isn't any secret. In fact, I
think I've even tweeted this. I mean,
you can just tell it I'm going to bed.
Don't ask me for any questions. Every
time I've done that, it's ran for four
plus hours. So, it's like
>> really, yeah, there's there's no secret
here. It's just you just say, "Hey, I'm
walking away. Don't ask me for any
input. And don't stop hacking." Like, I
want you to keep going. Keep going
deeper. Keep finding more bugs. Just
literally give it that prompt and it
won't it will not stop for hours.
>> That's very surprising.
>> Really?
>> That's interesting. Yeah, I I didn't
expect it to be that straightforward cuz
I thought that would get like compacted
away or something. I don't know.
>> You know, it does get compacted. So, I
guess maybe it it's working because I
have a good claw MD. But you should just
tell I mean if you want to, you can be
like, "Hey, I'm walking away. You're
going to end up compacting. So, just
keep good notes about where you were and
what you were doing." But in general, I
think that's kind of already built into
their compact um script or to their
compact.
>> It might survive it. it might survive
it. You know, it might just say like
when it's compacting it might be like,
oh,
>> it writes itself a big new prompt to
start and so it does survive most of the
time. Oh, this is actually a really
great tip for the listener. I probably
also shouldn't share, but um on those
compaction loops, if when it comes out
of compaction, it reaches a context
limit before there's any steps in
between. It can't like roll back or
compact. That happens most likely when
you have sub aents with like a lot of
sub aents. So, my personal fix for this
is to tell it not to use more than two
to three sub agents. Anytime it spawned
four or more, I end up getting into um a
place where it can't compact. And I
can't go back and have it not compact
because whenever you go back to redo
that to like jump back a few loops, you
have to hit like escape twice and you go
up and then you press up and you go to
like a separate chat. But when it's
running autonomously overnight or
whatever, you can't go up. And when it
compacts, there's no there's no message
to jump back to. And so then you're in
the situation where you have to detangle
it. And for me, I then have to open a
new instance and tell it to go read all
the context from this other session and
get all the context it needs to get
started again. So my in my experience,
the best way to limit that, especially
if you're going to run overnight, is to
be like, don't use more than two sub
agents.
>> Okay. All right. That's a that's a good
that's a good point. I think uh I
haven't run into that issue, which means
I'm probably not using it properly yet.
>> No, no. I think we're I think you you
often just like have four separate
instances so they're probably not using
sub agents that much and you're also
interacting with it often. You're not
like having it run overnight. So those
are the two reasons
>> you're running everything from discord,
right? You don't really interact with
the the like cloud code command line as
often, right?
>> Uh I would say there's I have basically
three modes. Um I'm I'm okay to share
this. I think one is I co-hack with
cloud code on my desktop and I do that a
lot and I do that all through iTerm just
through the terminal in the normal cloud
code CLI
>> that's probably let's say 50% of my
usage um and then the other 50% yeah I I
have like a Discord bot that basically
mimics cloud code in in like a Discord
thread and I use that anytime I'm doing
stuff on my VPS
um and then it's a very similar setup
for the automated bot that I've created
that you know, I use with JD and we um
yeah, same. It's all through Discord.
It's all managed through Discord.
>> I just find it so much nicer. Like I'm
in kids carine. I'm, you know,
>> yeah,
>> I'm doing my business.
>> That's one thing that I struggle with.
Yeah. With Mike setup, which is just
T-Mox, four pains, you know, let's go.
All working on different stuff. By the
time I'm done prompting one of them, the
other one's done and I can just kind of
jump jump. Yeah. Um, but yeah, the
remote control functionality is is
getting better, but it's not perfect,
you know. Um, so it's crazy. I think I
talked about it on the pod last week and
it's already better, you know, like
they're already Yeah. Oh, yeah. Yeah, it
is
>> for sure. It's not perfect, but it is
better. So,
>> if anybody I know you were asking me and
I didn't have a good answer to this
before the pod started. If anyone's
using cloud code in the desktop app, I
think there's probably some like really
big wins there. Like I don't like that
when you hit control O it only shows you
the output from the most recent command.
You can't go up and see the output from
like previous commands. And then
sometimes I hit control O my computer
will just like lock up because I think
it's trying to load like a bajillion you
know characters
>> from like a bunch of different output
over there. And so yeah um the primogen
which is like a you know if people don't
know he's like a software dev influencer
and he's really funny and really great
but he is always making fun of how bad
their TUI is. I've heard that open open
code is much better, but I but back
whenever they like stopped allowing
cloud code to be used in thirdparty
services or something. I never I never
went down that route and figured it out.
But yeah.
>> Yeah, the subsidation is OP, man. It
really is. That's one thing that we were
even talking about with with Shift. Like
I think Shift is super good in Kaido,
>> but the the problem is it, you know,
isn't free. And I'm just so like hooked
on this crack of like I don't even have
to think about the tokens because cloud
cloud max is like you know bucks and
then I'm I'm good,
>> you know. Um so yeah it is it is uh it
is really crazy that
>> cloud code is has that market cornered
because of the the subsidation. Um all
right man. Um let's just talk well first
I I think we should go back and
summarize everything that what we what
we just said here. Okay. So here's
here's what I understand about the best
practices that you mentioned on this pod
and you can interject whenever you want
and give me your thoughts. Okay. So here
we go. First we need to be you know pair
hacking with with claude. We have to we
must
>> and one of the uh highest value things
that you can do to do that is get the
Kaido mode skill. Get it hooked into
Kaido. get it using your proxy so you
can see what it's doing and adding uh
value, you know, handing things off to
you, right? And making things easier for
you to hack with, right? What what I'll
often do with it, hand it a bunch of
JavaScript files, recreate all of these
HTTP requests in kind of replay
sessions. Boom.
>> You know, it's beautiful.
>> Um so that that's one one thing. The
other thing is giving it a note
structure that it can use. So, we've got
notes, you got leads, you got um
primitives, and then you've got reports
and and giving it that structure so it
knows how to store information in a way
that you can digest. Well,
>> yeah, for hacking locally, if you're
hacking locally and not remotely, uh I
didn't even think about this. I
definitely should have mentioned it. The
Kaido skill actually lets you pipe
straight to the findings um tab. So, you
can just have it goes so when you're
hacking, you'll get the little red dot
and then you'll know to look. Yeah,
>> that's a good that's a good call as
well. Um, and then we're building
skills. Skills are either pieces of
information or tools or both that uh
Claude can use and will rag into context
as needed.
>> Uh, don't Yeah, rag. It doesn't use rag
there. Um, rag is almost
>> it did.
>> Interesting.
>> Uh, yeah, I it might if you have above a
certain amount, but um I think like up
to at least 35 or 50 or something, it it
basically sees the front matter. So, you
actually huge tip. Sorry, huge tip. We
should have mentioned already the front
matter for skills in the skill andd uh
file um has a description and a name
that's what is auto injected into the
context when you launch claude.
>> Okay.
>> So if you so if you have rules like use
this skill win put that in the
description of the front matter at the
top of the skill.md
for your skills and that is auto
injected at execution time into the um
into the prompt like the system prompt
that you use. this
>> that's not happening at the LLM level
right with rag it is happening at load
to skill level which makes sense because
that's why we see it load to skill you
know okay okay I understand
>> usually people say usually when people
say rag they mean like embeddings based
search and um by default cloud code
doesn't do any embeddings based search
that I know of
>> okay nice um so we load these skills up
these skills give us information and uh
tools to do things and we want to try to
do this when Claude does not have access
to uh specific pieces of information or
specific ways that we want it done.
>> That's right.
>> Um it, you know, we certainly can give
it uh ways to do things if we want
assurance that it will actually try
those things, but we should also caveat
it at the end of whatever skills MD file
or whatever with uh hey, but
>> use your creativity as well. Don't be
like cornered by this skill, right? Does
that make is that is that accurate?
>> That's exactly right.
>> Okay. I wonder I wonder what the impact
of these cumulative tips will have on
everyone's hack bots. Frick frick. Um
okay. And then you know last piece is
like give it information about you and
and how you need things done. So you
know creds to your VPS you know to a you
know cornered little document route or
whatever. Um you know that sort of
thing. And so it knows how to like host
things or um present information in a
way that is is good for you, right? It's
sort of aligned with the notes thing,
but giving it more giving it access to
things that you want it to be able to
access for the specific mission. Like,
okay, here are my creds to this, you
know, app that I want you to hack. Here
are these, you know, cookies that I want
you to use. That sort of thing. Um and
and that could be at runtime, right, via
the prompt or it could be in the skills
as well.
>> That's right. Um, all right, man. All
right, let's do this. Let's do this
[__] All right.
>> Well, so one thing that we didn't
mention yet that I know we talked about
potentially mentioning is um agents
versus folders. You want to talk about
that?
>> Okay. Yeah. Yeah. Let's do it. Yep. Mhm.
>> So, in my opinion, you like and in most
people's opinion, you don't want
>> Explain that first. What do you mean
agents versus folders?
>> Yeah. So one thing we didn't really talk
about but some of the major components
are like agents which agents if anyone
doesn't know in cloud code are and this
is probably true in codeex I'm not sure
but agents are a specific system prompt
with a specific set of skills or even
tools like command line tools that it's
like whitelisted to use
and um because of that you can make like
a you know pin tester agent if if you're
going to be using cloud code for lots of
stuff like finances and you know PDFs
and other other junk but you're also
going to be using it for pin testing you
could use a pin tester agent or like bug
bounty agent for that alternatively and
I think this is the method that I like
slightly prefer you can you can launch
cloud code out of a folder on your
computer and in that folder your cloud
folder will only be loaded if you're in
that folder. So the way that cloud code
works is you have in your home directory
or whatever wherever you've saved it off
as like your main cloud directory you
have acloud folder which includes like a
cloudmd and skills and agents right but
then if you're in a subfolder it looks
there first and includes that as well as
the parent folder so you know if you put
in your home.cloudmd cloudmd you know
this is my home and then you put in a
you know another folder in thecloudcloud
MD this is the folder and then you were
able to go and you like proxied the
traffic it would have both of those in
the context if you launched it from that
folder so
>> okay
>> this has this has like two ways that it
could be used positively by our
listeners one is you could have a bug
bounty folder where you are a hacking
folder where you load all of your skills
and your and your custom prompts and if
you launch it out of your home directory
it won't have all that so you can like
use it for normal day-to-day stuff
that's not hacking. But if you launch it
from inside that folder, it will have
those things. Um, so that's one way. The
other thing you could do um is have a
target is like launch cloud code from a
target specific folder and have its cla
MD have the information, the top level
information about that target. So you
could have like a a flow where anytime
you say like okay I want to start
hacking on X the first thing Claude does
is go and creates a targets folder for
that target and then goes and pulls the
policy page from hacker one or whatever
and puts that policy in the cloud MD in
that folder. So then when you launch it
from that folder later it now has that
target specific information loaded in
automatically
>> dude.
Oh gosh there's so much possibilities
with this. my as you're talking my brain
is just sitting I I feel like I kind of
you know normally I'm like guiding the
conversation and and you know leading
hosting on this podcast but as you start
talking about these things I just sit
here and I start churning you know and
and my brain's like this is what you're
going to do right after you get off this
freaking podcast you know just like oh
[__] okay so anyway thanks for thanks
for sharing all that information um you
know there's a couple more things that
we could do here but I actually want the
you know extra 10 minutes back to uh to
go and actually implement that stuff.
So, let's uh let's cut it here and let's
uh let's get in the HTP requests. So,
>> perfect.
>> All right. Peace, man.
>> Peace.
>> And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh or if
you want to support the show, head over
to ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, hackalongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunters guild
if you're a full-time hunter. It's a
great time, trust me. All right, I'll
see you there.